Guide to the Group Research, Inc. Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Topical Files
  - Midwest Employer's Council, Inc. (Box 219)
  - Midwest Labor Council (Box 220)
  - Midwest Research Institute (Box 220)
  - Migratory Labor -- farm (Box 220)
  - Milbank, Jeremiah, Jr. (Box 220)
  - Milione, Victor (Box 220)
    [Right-wing activist associated with the Intercollegiate Society of Individualists, Young Americans for Freedom, and Americans for Competitive Enterprise among others. See also Americans for the Competitive Enterprise System as well as the Group Research directory under E. Victor Milione.]
  - "Militant Truth" Patterson, Sherman A. (editor) (Box 220)
  - Military Benefit Association (Box 220)
  - Military Chaplains Association (Box 220)
    [See also Dr. Karl Bennet Justus.]
  - Military Reform Institute (Box 220)
  - Miller, Donald L. (Box 220)
  - Miller Brewing Company Miller, Fred (Box 220)
  - Miller, Giles (Box 220)
  - Miller, Harold (M.D.) (Box 220)
  - Miller, Hobart (Box 220)
  - Miller, Howard (Box 220)
  - Miller, Paul and Marion, Los Angeles, CA (Box 220)
    [Former FBI undercover agents See also the Group Research directory under Paul and Marion Miller.]
  - Miller, Raymond ("Dr.") (Box 220)
  - Miller, Robert J. (M.D.) (Box 220)
  - Miller, William E. (Box 220)
  - Milliken Family, Spartanburg, SC (Box 220)
    [See also Deering-Milliken Corporation and Foundation and the Group Resarch directory under Minot K. Milliken.]
  - Milliken, Roger, Spartanburg, SC (Box 220)
    [Former president and director, Deering, Milliken and Company, Inc. See also Deering-Milliken Corporation and Foundation and the Group Research directory under Roger Milliken.]
  - Mills, Wilbur D. (Rep.), D-AR (Box 220)
  - Milne, Richard (Box 220)
  - Ministry of Christ Church, Inc. (Box 221)
  - Minneci, Christ S. (Box 221)
  - Minneapolis Daily American Bob White Column (Box 221)
  - Minnesota Citizens Legislative League (Box 221)
  - Minnesota Committee for State-National Sovereignty (Box 221)
  - Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing (Box 221)
  - Minnesota, University of, Twin Cities, MN (Box 221)
  - Minority of One, The (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Miscellaneous publications (Box 221)
  - Minutemen "Congressional Record" clippings (Box 221)
  - Minutemen General (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, -1963 (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1964 (Box 221)
  - Minutement Newspaper clippings, 1965 (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1966 (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 221)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 222)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1969 (Box 222)
  - Minutemen Newspaper clippings, 1970 (Box 222)
  - Minute Men of America, Stewart, FL (Box 222)
  - Minute Women of America (Box 222)
  - Mission Mountain College, Polson, MT (Box 222)
  - Mission to Europe's Millions (Box 222)
  - Mississippi Association of Methodist Ministers and Laymen (Box 222)
  - Mississippi Sovereign Commission (Box 222)
  - Missouri Freedom Forum Fund, Missouri Military Academy, Mexico, MO (Box 222)
  - Missouri Military Academy (Box 222)
  - Mitchell, Henry (Rev.) (Box 222)
  - Mitchell, Joseph M. (Box 222)
    [See also Newburgh, NY file.]
  - Mitchell, Reg (Box 222)
  - Modern Age (Box 222)
  - Moffit, Jack (Box 222)
  - Mohr, Jack (Col.) (Box 222)
  - Moley, Raymond (Box 222)
  - Mollenhoff, Clark R. (Box 222)
  - Molthrop, David M. Washington, DC (Box 222)
    [Former executive Vice President, Committee on State Sovereignty, Inc. See also Committee on State Sovereignty, Inc. and the Group Research directory under David M. Molthrop.]
  - Montana Citizens Group (Box 222)
  - Montana Power Company, The (Box 222)
  - Montana Research Associates (Box 222)
  - Montanans for Better Citizenship (Box 222)
  - Mont Pelerin Society (Box 223)
  - Moore, Aubrey L. (Rev.) (Box 223)
  - Moore Fund, Hugh (Box 223)
  - Moore, Margaret (Box 223)
  - Moore, Tom (Pastor) (Box 223)
  - Moral Majority, 1988- (Box 223)
  - Moral Majority, 1986- (Box 223)
  - Moral Majority, 1985- (Box 223)
  - Moral Majority, 1984- (Box 224)
  - Moral Majority, 1983- (Box 224)
  - Moral Majority, 1982- (Box 224)
  - Moral Majority, 1982- (Box 225)
  - Moral Majority, 1981- (Box 225)
  - Moral Majority (Box 225)
  - Moral Rearment (Box 226)
  - Moral Rearmament (MRA) Newspaper clippings (Box 226)
    [Founder, Father Nathan Daniel Buchman See also the Group Research directory under Moral Rearmament (MRA).]
  - Moral Rearmament (MRA) Magazine and "Congressional Record" clippings (Box 226)
  - Moral Rearmament (MRA) Publications (Box 226)
  - Moran, Richard B. (Brig.Gen.) (Box 227)
  - Moreell, Ben (Admiral), Pittsburgh, PA and Washington, DC (Box 227)
    [Former chairman, Americans for Constitutional Action See also Americans for Constitutional Action and the Group Research directory under Admiral Ben Moreell.]
  - Morgan, Gerald D. (Box 227)
    [ ]
  - Morley, Felix Muskett, Gibson Island, MD (Box 227)
    [Writer and educator See also the Group Research directory under Felix Muskett Morley.]
  - Morley, John K. (Box 227)
  - Mormon Church (Box 227)
  - Mormon Church, 1973- (Box 227)
  - Mormon Church, 1993- (Box 227)
  - Morris, Robert, Dallas, TX (Box 228)
    [Former president, Defenders of American Liberties See also the Group Research directory under Robert Morris, "No Wonder We are Losing" (a book by Morris), and "Disarmament: Weapon of Conquest" (another book by Morris).]
  - Catholic Standard Press Morriss, Frank (Box 228)
    [Columnist]
  - Morton Charitable Trust, Sterling (Box 228)
  - Moseley, Alexander (Box 228)
  - Moseley, C. C. Glendale, CA (Box 228)
    [Chairman and president, Grand Central Industrial Centre and Grand Central Aircraft Company See also the Group Research directory under C. C. Moseley. ]
  - Moseley Foundation (Box 228)
  - Mosely, George Van Horne (Gen.) (Box 228)
  - Moser, Charles (Box 228)
  - Mote, Lynn E. "Bud" (Box 228)
  - Mothers Against Chavez (Box 228)
  - Mothers' Crusade for Victory over Communism (Box 228)
  - Mothers for Moral America (Box 228)
  - Mothers of Servicemen (Box 228)
  - Motion Picture Alliance for the Preservation of American Ideals (Box 229)
  - Mott Foundation (Box 229)
  - Mott, William C. (Admiral) (Box 229)
  - Mountain Valley Charitable Trust Fund (Box 229)
  - Movement for the Federation of the Americas (Box 229)
  - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel (Box 229)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick (Sen.), D-NY (Box 229)
  - Mt. Ararat Foundation, Inc. (Box 229)
  - Mullen, Robert V. (Box 229)
  - Muncaster, Robert (Box 229)
  - Mundt, Karl E. (Box 229)
  - "Muncipal and Economic Research" (Box 229)
  - Munson, Lyle Hugh, New York, NY (Box 229)
    [Founder, The Bookmailer See also the Bookmailer and the Group Research directory under Lyle Hugh Munson.]
  - Murchison, Clint (Box 229)
  - M. J. Murdock Charitable Trust (Box 229)
  - Murdoch, Rupert (Box 229)
  - Murphy, George (Box 229)
  - Murphy, John J. (Hon.), Somerville, MA (Box 229)
  - Murphy, Richard R. (Box 229)
  - Murphy, Robert W. (Box 229)
  - Murray, Charles (Box 229)
  - "Red Web Over Congress" [pamphlet] Murray, James E. (Sen.), D-MT (Box 229)
  - Muse, Vance (Box 229)
  - Music (Box 229)
  - Mutual Broadcasting System (Box 229)
  - My Country Society, Inc. (Box 229)
  - Myers, Kenneth L. and Ellen (Box 229)
  - Narmic (National Action/Research on the Military Industrial Complex) (Box 230)
  - Narmic (National Action/Research on the Military Industrial Complex) (Box 230)
  - Nash Publishing (Box 230)
  - Nashville Civic Forum (Box 230)
  - Nathaniel Branden Institute (Box 230)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (Box 230)
  - National Action Committee on Labor Law Reform (Box 230)
  - National Action Committee to Preserve the Ban on Secondary Boycotts (Box 230)
  - National Affairs Seminar (Box 230)
  - National Agricultural Institute (Box 230)
  - National Agricultural Press Association (Box 230)
  - National Agricultural Limestone Institute (Box 230)
    [Folder empty. See also National Limestone Institute. ]
  - National Alliance of Russian Solidarists (Box 230)
  - National Alliance of Senior Citizens (Box 230)
  - National Alliance of Senior Citizens, 1981 (Box 230)
  - National American Flag Week (Box 231)
    [Folder empty. See also Committee for the Observance of American Flag Week. ]
  - National Anti-Communist League of America [NACLA] (Box 231)
  - National Associated Businessmen, Inc. (Box 231)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 231)
  - National Association for the Advancement of White People (NAAWP) (Box 231)
  - National Association for Constitutional Government (Box 231)
  - National Association for Preservation of Free Enterprise (Box 231)
  - National Association for Uniformed Services (Box 231)
  - National Association of Americans for the Preservation of the Caucasian (Box 231)
  - National Association of Cooperatives (Box 231)
  - National Association of Evangelicals (Box 231)
  - National Association of Home Builders (Box 231)
  - National Association of Internal Revenue Employees (Box 231)
  - National Association of Manufacturers General (Box 231)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, General, 1976 (Box 232)
  - National Association of Manufacturers General, 1979 (Box 232)
  - National Association of Manufacturers Newspaper clippings (Box 232)
  - National Association of Manufacturers Farm Policy (Box 232)
  - National Association of Manufacturers Taxes (Box 232)
  - National Association of Manufacturers Against organized labor (Box 232)
  - National Association of Professional Educators (Box 232)
  - National Association of Property Owners, The (Box 233)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards (Box 233)
  - National Association of State Militia (Box 233)
  - National Association of Youth Councils on Civic Affairs (Box 233)
  - National Audience Board, Inc. (Box 233)
  - National Bellamy Award (Box 233)
  - National Black Silent Majority Committee, The (Box 233)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Box 233)
  - National Business League (Box 233)
  - National Businessmen's Council (ADA) (Box 233)
  - National Catholic Welfare Conference (Box 233)
  - National Center for Public Policy Research, The (Box 233)
  - National Center for Voluntary Action (Box 233)
  - National Christian Action Coalition (Box 233)
  - National Christians Citizens Committee (Box 233)
    [Former Chairman, Gerri von Frellick See also the Group Research directory under Special Reports -- "National Christians Citizens Committee."]
  - National Citizens Action Network (Box 233)
  - National Citizens Committee to Curb Inflation (Box 233)
  - National Citizens Council for Better Schools (Box 233)
  - National Civic Affairs Bureau (Box 233)
  - National Coalition for a Responsible Congress (Box 233)
  - National Coalition for America's Survival to Promote a Human Rights and National Survival Program (Box 233)
  - National Coalition for Children (Box 233)
  - National Commission on Constitutional Government (Box 233)
  - National Committee [??] Operation Patriot (Box 233)
  - National Committee Reapportionment Crisis (Box 233)
  - National Committee against Discrimination in Housing (Box 233)
  - National Committee against Fluoridation (Box 233)
  - National Committee against Forced Busing (Box 233)
  - National Committee against the Treaty of Moscow (Box 233)
  - National Committee for a Constitutional Convention (Box 233)
  - National Committee for a Representative Congress, Washington, DC (Box 234)
    [Founded by Robert H. Austin See also the Group Research directory under National Committee for a Representative Congress.]
  - National Committee for an Effective Congress (Box 234)
  - National Committee for Economic Freedom, Los Angeles, CA (Box 234)
    [See also Willis E. Stone and the Group Research directory under National Committee for Economic Freedom.]
  - National Committee For Effective Government (Box 234)
  - National Committee for Responsible Patriotism (Box 234)
  - National Committee for the Liberation of China (Box 234)
  - National Committee for the Reelection of Walter H. Judd (Box 234)
  - National Committee for the Support of the Public Schools (Box 234)
  - National Committee of Christian Laymen (Box 234)
  - National Committee of Liberty and Justice for All (Box 234)
  - National Committee of Republicans for Victory in '72 (Box 234)
  - National Committee on Monetary Policy (Box 234)
  - National Committee on Tithing in Investment (Box 234)
  - National Committee on United States-China Relations (Box 234)
  - National Committee to Abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) (Box 234)
  - National Committee to Limit Federal Taxing Powers (Box 234)
  - National Committee to Preserve the Connally Amendment and American Sovereignty (Box 234)
  - National Committee to Restore Internal Security (Box 234)
  - National Community Relations Advisory Council (Box 234)
  - National Conference for New Politics (Box 234)
  - National Confederation of American Ethnic Groups (Box 235)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box 235)
  - National Confererence of Citizens for Religious Freedom (Box 235)
  - National Conference on Citizenship (Box 235)
  - National Conference on International Economic and Social Development (Box 235)
  - National Congress for Educational Excellence (Box 235)
  - National Congress of Parents and Teachers (Box 235)
  - National Conservative Council (Box 235)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC), 1987- (Box 235)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC), 1985 (Box 235)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC), 1984- (Box 236)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC), 1982- (Box 236)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC), 1981- (Box 236)
  - National Conservative Political Action Committee (NCPAC) (Box 237)
  - National Constitutional Voters Organization (Box 237)
  - National Coordinating Council for Constructive Action (Box 237)
  - National Council for American Education (Box 237)
  - National Council for Civic Responcibility (Box 237)
  - National Council for Labor's Rank and File (Box 237)
  - National Council for Prevention of Drug Abuse (Box 237)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the USA (Box 237)
  - National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor (Box 237)
  - National Counter Intelligence Corps Association (Box 237)
  - National Defender (Box 237)
  - National Defense Council (Box 237)
  - National Democratic Institute for International Affairs (Box 238)
  - National Dividend Plan (Box 238)
  - National Economic Council, New York, NY and Utica, NY, 1972- (Box 238)
    [See also Mark Manderville Jones and the Group Research directory under National Economic Council.]
  - National Economic Council Hart, Merwin K. (Box 238)
    [Right-wing activist See also Merwin Hart and Economic Council Letter as well as the Group Research directory under Merwin K. Hart.]
  - National Economic Research Associates (Box 238)
  - National Education Association (NEA) Publications (Box 238)
  - National Education Association (NEA) General (Box 238)
  - National Educational Institute for Agriculture (Box 238)
  - National Enquirer (Box 238)
  - National Exchange Club (Box 238)
  - National Farmers Guild (Box 238)
  - National Farmers Organization (Box 239)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Conservative Organizations (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Independent Business "Mandate" (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Independent Business Press Service (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Independent Business (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Independent Farm Organizations (Box 239)
  - National Federation of Independent Unions (Box 239)
  - National Forum Foundation (Box 239)
  - National Foundation for Economic Stability (Box 239)
  - National Foundation for Education in American Citizenship (NFEAC), Indianapolis, IN (Box 239)
    [Associated with Human Events, Inc. and George S. Olive and Company. See also the Group Research directory under National Foundation for Education in American Citizenship.]
  - National Foundation to Increase Public Understanding of Congress (Box 239)
  - National Freedom Education Center, King's College, Briarcliff Manor, NY (Box 239)
  - National Freedom of Employment Committee (Box 239)
  - National Fund for a New Congress, Inc. (Box 239)
  - National Goals Foundation (Box 239)
  - National Goals, Inc. (Box 239)
  - National Grange (Box 240)
  - National Greenback Party (Box 240)
  - National Guard Local Groups (Box 240)
  - National Guard Association of the United States (Box 240)
  - National Guardian (Box 240)
  - National Health Federation (Box 240)
  - National Heritage Foundation (Box 240)
  - National Indignation Convention, TX (Box 240)
    [See also Frank McGehee, American Freedom Rallies, and the Group Research directory under National Indignation Convention and under Special Reports -- National Indignation Convention.]
  - National Industrial Conference Board (Box 240)
  - National Industrial Council (Box 240)
  - National Information Center (Box 240)
  - National Information Center (Box 240)
  - National Information Bureau, Inc. (Box 240)
  - National Initiative/Referendum Association (Box 240)
  - National Insider (Box 240)
  - National Institute for Disaster Mobilization, Inc. (Box 240)
  - National Institute for Law/Order/Justice (Box 240)
  - National Institute for Public Policy (Box 240)
  - National Institute of Education (Box 240)
  - National Institute of Public Affairs (Box 240)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences (Box 240)
  - National Intelligence Study Center (Box 240)
  - National Interest (Box 240)
  - National Junior Achievement (Box 240)
  - National Justice Foundation (Box 240)
  - National Labor Group (Box 241)
  - National Labor - Management Foundation (Box 241)
  - National Labor Reform Committee (Box 241)
  - National Land Title Reclamation Association (Box 241)
  - National Law Enforcement Committee (Box 241)
  - National Lawyers Guild (Box 241)
  - National Legal Center for the Public Interest (Box 242)
  - National Legal Center for the Public Interest, 1983- (Box 242)
  - National Liberation Front (NLF) (Box 242)
  - National Liberty Foundation of Valley Forge, Inc. (Box 242)
  - National Limestone Institute (Box 242)
    [Formerly National Agricultural Limestone Institute.]
  - National Limestone Institute (Box 242)
  - National Livestock and Meat Board (Box 242)
  - National Lumber Manufacturers Association (Box 242)
  - National Management Association, The (Box 242)
  - National Media Analysis, Inc. (Box 242)
  - National Medical Association (Box 242)
  - National Medical-Physical Research Foundation, Inc. (Box 242)
  - National Military-Industrial and Educational Conference (Box 242)
  - National Military Industrial Conference (Box 242)
  - National Movement of Rightist Students (Box 242)
  - National Municipal League (Box 242)
  - National Negro Congress of Racial Pride (Box 242)
  - National Opinion Poll (Box 243)
  - National Opinion Party (Box 243)
  - National Party (Box 243)
  - National Party of America (Box 243)
  - National Patrick Henry Organization, Inc. (Box 243)
  - National Perspectives (Box 243)
  - National Petitioning Committee for Constitutional Government of America (Box 243)
  - National Popular Government League (Box 243)
  - National Precinct Workers (Box 243)
  - National Press Inc. (Box 243)
  - National Prohibition Party (Box 243)
  - National Putnam Letters Committee (Box 243)
  - National Reclamation Association (Box 243)
  - National Renaissance Party (Box 243)
  - National Reprint Service (Box 243)
  - National Republic Organization (Box 243)
  - National Republican Congressional Committee (Box 243)
  - "National Republican Statesman" (Box 243)
  - National Research Bureau (Box 243)
  - "National Review", 1972- (Box 244)
  - "National Review" (Box 244)
  - "National Review" (Box 244)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA), 1991- (Box 244)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA), 1980- (Box 245)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) (Box 245)
    [See also Lobbying.]
  - National Rural Electric Cooperative Assocation (Box 245)
  - National School Boards Assocation (Box 245)
  - National Schools Committee for Economic Education (Box 245)
  - National Security Agency (Box 245)
  - National Security Seminar (Box 245)
  - "National Sentinel, The" (Box 245)
  - National Services, Inc. (Box 245)
  - National Shooting Sports Foundation (Box 246)
  - National Small Business Association (Box 246)
    [See also National Small Business Men's Association.]
  - National Small Business Men's Association (Box 246)
    [See also National Small Business Association.]
  - National Socialist Party of America (Box 246)
  - National Society Colonial Daughters of the Seventeenth Century (Box 246)
  - National Society for Constitutional Security (Box 246)
  - National Sojourners, Inc. (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, Birmingham, AL (headquarters), -1962 (Box 246)
    [See also Group Research directory under National States Rights Party.]
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1963 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1964 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1965 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1966 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1967 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1968 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Clippings, 1969-70 (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party "Congressional Record" and magazine clippings (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Financial (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party General (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Letters -- Promotional and other (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Miscellaneous distributed materials (Box 246)
  - National States Rights Party Newsletters (Box 247)
  - National Strategy Information Center (Box 247)
  - National Student Association (Box 247)
  - National Student Committee for Victory in Vietnam (Box 247)
  - National Student Coordinated Committee for Freedom in Vietnam and Southeast Asia (Box 247)
  - National Sunday School Association (Box 247)
  - National Tax Equality Association (Box 247)
  - National Tax Equality Association (Box 247)
  - National Tax Equality Association (Box 248)
  - National Tax Limitation Committee (Box 249)
  - National Tax Reform Committee (Box 249)
  - National Taxaction, Inc. (Box 249)
  - National Taxpayers Association (Box 249)
  - National Taxpayers Investigative Fund (Box 249)
  - National Taxpayers Union, 1991- (Box 249)
  - National Taxpayers Union, 1982- (Box 249)
  - National Taxpayers Union, The (Box 249)
  - National Thrift Committee (Box 250)
  - National Urban League, Inc. (Box 250)
  - National War College, Washington, DC (Box 250)
  - National White Americans Party (Box 250)
  - National White People's Party (Box 250)
  - National Write Your Congressman Club, Dallas, TX (Box 250)
    [Founded by David N. Adamson. See also the Group Research directory under National Write Your Congressman Club.]
  - National Youth Alliance Macdonald, Andrew "The Turner Diaries", 1976- (Box 250)
  - National Youth Alliance, 1971-5 (Box 250)
  - National Youth Alliance (Box 250)
    [(carte-Tifer)]
  - National Youth Alliance (Box 250)
  - Nationalist Party Reynolds, Robert (Box 251)
  - "Nation's Agriculture" (Box 251)
    [Published by the American Farm Bureau Federation.]
  - Nation's Business (Box 251)
  - Nation-Wide Committee (Box 251)